<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://libretime.org/blog</id>
    <title>LibreTime Blog</title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://libretime.org/blog"/>
    <subtitle>LibreTime Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://libretime.org/img/icon.svg</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LibreTime 3.0.0 beta.0, finally!]]></title>
        <id>/2022/09/17/libretime-v3-beta.0</id>
        <link href="https://libretime.org/blog/2022/09/17/libretime-v3-beta.0"/>
        <updated>2022-09-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greetings LibreTime enthusiast's and friends!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Greetings LibreTime enthusiast's and friends!</p><p>We are happy to announce that we <a href="/docs/releases/3.0.0-beta.0/">released LibreTime <code>v3.0.0-beta.0</code> yesterday</a>! 🎉</p><p>This is our very first blog post, and they should be as irregular as LibreTime releases! We changed from the monthly community meetings to something less timezone sensitive, such as blog posts.</p><p>We will go through the notable changes in the recent release of LibreTime.</p><p>A <strong>lot</strong> of work has been put into LibreTime to finalize the forking from AirTime, and provide a comfortable base for future works.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="versions-and-supported-distributions-releases">Versions, and supported distributions releases<a class="hash-link" href="#versions-and-supported-distributions-releases" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>We drafted a <a href="/docs/developer-manual/development/releases/#distributions-releases-support">supported distributions releases and versions support policy</a>, that will help us to know when to drop support for distributions releases, and help you to plan for a distributions upgrades.</p><p>The important bits are:</p><ul><li>New LibreTime releases will only target the current stable distributions releases.</li><li>Maintenance only releases will provide bug and security fixes for old stable distributions releases until they reach their end of life.</li></ul><p>Note that the <a href="/docs/releases/3.0.0-beta.0/#-deprecation-and-removal">release note for LibreTime <code>v3.0.0-beta.0</code></a> announced some major deprecation.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-missing-from-airtime-">What is missing from AirTime ?<a class="hash-link" href="#what-is-missing-from-airtime-" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>I would expect that most of AirTime users already migrated to LibreTime using one of the many alpha versions, for those who didn't migrated yet, you will have to install LibreTime <code>&lt;3.1</code> before upgrading to any newer versions.</p><p>Some incomplete or non functional features from AirTime were removed in LibreTime:</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/libretime/libretime/pull/1327" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The <strong>My podcasts</strong> feature has been removed.</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/libretime/libretime/issues/42" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The <strong>Line in recording</strong> feature was not added.</a></li><li>(I probably missed a few others...)</li></ul><p>Those feature might be reimplemented in the future, any contribution are welcome!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="running-inside-containers">Running inside containers<a class="hash-link" href="#running-inside-containers" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>This has been awaited for quite some time: you can now <a href="/docs/admin-manual/setup/install/#using-docker-compose">run LibreTime inside containers</a> 🎉 ! A <a href="https://github.com/libretime/libretime/tree/main/docker/example" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">docker-compose example</a> is available in the repository.</p><p>Please help us test it and give us feedback, we really appreciate any help!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-new-configuration-file">A new configuration file<a class="hash-link" href="#a-new-configuration-file" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>A lot has moved with regards to configuring LibreTime. A lot of settings from the database moved to the configuration file to simplify the configuration of LibreTime.</p><p>This will allow us to add more options for advanced use cases, such as ssl input harbors, HLS outputs or your own Liquidsoap scripts.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="improvement-for-development">Improvement for development<a class="hash-link" href="#improvement-for-development" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>LibreTime might be hard to contribute to without having a good understanding of the project in general. A lot of work has been made to clean and modernize parts of LibreTime, by simplifying the file structure of the project and the naming, adding typing definitions or development tools to help you write good code. To keep improving the developer experience, new contributions will have to include typings and tests.</p><p>Though, with the new docker-compose setup, setting up a development environment is really easy! Feel free to test it by making a contribution!</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="now-what-">Now what ?<a class="hash-link" href="#now-what-" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>We expect to cut the LibreTime 3.0.0 release in the next weeks. So please help us test LibreTime so we can fix bugs!</p><p>A few exiting features that are will be worked on once 3.0.0 is out:</p><ul><li>Liquidsoap 2.0 support</li><li>SSL input harbors</li><li>HLS streaming</li><li>Start embedding a new UI in parts of the legacy web application.</li></ul><p>If you feel <a href="https://opencollective.com/libretime" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">like paying us a beer, or a month rent</a>, we will really appreciate!</p><p>Cheers !</p><p>Jo</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jooola</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/jooola</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
</feed>